As you come into this world,
something else is also born.
RUMBLING
You begin your life, and
it begins a journey...
towards you.
It moves slowly, but it never stops.
Wherever you go, whatever path you take,
it will follow.
Never faster, never slower, always coming.
You will run.
It will walk.
You will rest.
It will not.
One day, you will linger
in the same place too long.
You will sit too still
or sleep too deep...
.. and when, too late, you rise to go...
.. you will notice a
second shadow next to yours.
Your life will then be over.
GASPING
HE COUGHS AND GASPS FOR AIR
RAVEN CAWS
If you think because
she is dead, I am weak,
then you understand very little.
If you were any part of killing
her, and you're not afraid,
then you understand nothing at all.
So, for your own sake, understand this.
I am the Doctor.
I'm coming to find you,
and I will never, ever stop.
The equipment in that room is consistent
with an augmented ultra
long-range teleport.
So, I'm not more than a single
light year from where I was,
and I'm in the same time zone.
When the sun sets, I'll be able
to establish an exact position
by the stars. Then you'll have a choice.
Come out, show yourself,
or keep on hiding.
Clara said I shouldn't take revenge.
You should know, I don't always listen.
Oh, what's this?
Well, are you gardeners? I hate gardening!
What sort of a person has a
power complex about flowers?
It's dictatorship for inadequates.
Or to put it another
way, it's dictatorship.
Come on! Chop, chop!
The Doctor will see you now!
Show me what you've got!
I just watched my best friend die in
agony. My day can't get any worse.
Let's see what we can do about yours!
STATIC HISSES
LOUD THUMP
THUMPING FOOTSTEPS
FOOTSTEPS GET LOUDER
FLIES BUZZ
HE GROANS
I know you.
I've seen you before!
I used to know a trick, back
when I was young and telepathic.
Clearly, you can't make an
actual psychic link with a door,
for one very obvious reason --
they're notoriously cross.
I mean, imagine life as a door.
People keep pushing past you.
All of that knocking,
but it's never for you.
And you get locked up every night,
so if you're just a little bit nice...
LOCK CLICKS
See, Clara?
Still got it.
But I... [HE MURMURS]
Um...
I can't actually see a way out of this...
I've finally run out of corridor.
There's a life summed up.
Now, this is new. I'm scared.
I just realised that I'm
actually scared of dying.
CLANG
SILENCE
Something I said?
What did I say?
Why did you stop?
CREAKING
LOUD CRASHING AND RUMBLING
SPRINGS CREAK
- Old. Very old.
- FOOTSTEPS THUMP
Possibly very, very old.
FLY BUZZES
When I was a very little boy,
there was an old lady who died.
They covered her in veils, but it was
a hot, sunny day, and the flies came.
It gave me nightmares for years. So,
who's been stealing my nightmares?
What am I here for?
You've known about me for
a very long time, right?
So, what is it?
Is it a trap?
Is it a prison?
No!
Is it a torture chamber?
Am I right?
Somebody really should know better.
Anyone who can put all of this
together and steal my bad dreams,
they should know better.
The secrets I have -- no chance.
No telling, not me.
I told you I was scared of
dying. And I wasn't lying either.
Advantage -- me!
Because you won't see THIS coming!
Sorry, I'm late! Jumped out of a window.
Certain death. Don't you
want to know how I survived?
Go on. Ask me!
No, of course I had to jump!
The first rule of being interrogated
is that you are the
only irreplaceable person
in the torture chamber.
The room is yours, so work it.
If they're going to
threaten you with death,
show them who's boss. Die faster!
You've seen me do that
more often than most.
Isn't that right, Clara?
Rule one of dying -- don't.
Rule two -- slow down.
You've got the rest of your life.
The faster you think,
the slower it will pass.
Concentrate! Assume you're going
to survive. Always assume that.
Imagine you've already survived.
There's a storm room in your mind.
Lock the door and think!
This is my storm room.
I always imagine that I'm
back in my Tardis, showing off,
telling you how I escaped,
making you laugh.
That's what I'm doing right now.
I am falling, Clara.
I'm dying.
And I'm going to explain
to you how I survived.
I can't wait to hear what I say.
I'm nothing without an audience.
BOOMING
One hope -- salt!
Thought I smelled it earlier. When
I broke the window, I was sure.
Salty air. This castle
is standing in the sea.
Diving into water from a great
height is no guarantee of survival.
I need to know exactly how far
I'm going to fall, and how fast.
Why do you think I threw the stool?
Fall time to impact...
- DISTANT SPLASH
- '.. seven seconds.'
Because you won't see this coming!
The wind resistance of the stool,
the atmospheric density...
.. the strength of the local gravity.
Am I spoiling the magic? I
work at this stuff, you know?
Should hit the water in about...
.. 0.02 seconds.
The chances of remaining conscious are...
LOUD SPLASH
CHALK TAPS ON CHALKBOARD
Can't I just sleep?
CHALK TAPS
Do I have to know everything?
Clara, I can't always...
CHALK TAPS
ECHOING SCREECHES
HE BREATHES DEEPLY
BOOTS SQUELCH
BREATHING
It keeps coming, Clara.
Wherever I go, it follows. Why?
- Why does it do that?
- CHALK TAPS
Always the teacher. What's
the right question, then?
TAPPING
It's following me.
Wherever I go, it's tracking me.
Slowly though. Scary lurching.
Scary!
These screens everywhere...
It's showing me exactly
where it is all the time,
how far it's got, how near.
Because it's trying to scare me!
Putting its breath on my neck.
That's the point! That's what
it's doing. This is theatre!
It's all about fear.
Working hypothesis --
I'm in a fully automated haunted
house. A mechanical maze.
CLATTERING
It's a killer puzzle box
designed to scare me to death,
and I'm trapped inside it.
HE CHUCKLES
Must be Christmas!
DOOR THUDS AND CREAKS OPEN
DRIPPING
DOOR CREAKS OPEN
DOOR SLAMS
FAINT BELLS CHIME
Another spade?
Someone wants me to dig.
What do you think, Clara?
Is someone trying to give me a hint?
- What would you do?
- CHALK TAPS
Yes. Yes, of course you would.
Which, let's be honest,
is what killed you.
So, someone is trying to tell me
that there's something important
buried in this garden.
That's almost the first
thing they tried to tell me.
Could be a trick.
Could be one of my predecessors.
Because I'm not the first
prisoner here, am I?!
All those skulls!
Wonder where they all went wrong.
Building this height,
creature that slow, so what...?
An hour.
HE BREATHES HEAVILY AND PANTS
FLY BUZZES
FLIES BUZZ
CREATURE SCREECHES
HE PANTS
THUDDING, HE GRUNTS
RUMBLING
HE PANTS
Physics of a triangle. You lose!
FOOTSTEPS THUMP
So?
It can set traps. That's OK.
I'm good at traps.
So, where are you off to?
Only one way in and one way out.
Well, seeing as you're going...
No, no. That's not right.
CRICKETS CHIRP
CLUNK!
SCRAPES GROUND
FLIES BUZZ
SCREECHING, HE YELLS
Well, that was another close one.
Or it will have been, once I've been
and gone and got myself out of it.
So, how am I going to do that?
Come on, teacher, ask me questions!
CHALK TAPS
I'm actually scared of dying.
The truth, yes.
But not any old truth, Clara.
This whole place is designed to
terrify me. I'm being interrogated.
It's not just truth it
wants. That's not enough.
It's confession.
I have to tell truths
I've never told before.
That's the only thing that stops it.
You see, the problem is...
.. Clara...
.. there are truths that I can never tell.
Not for anything.
But I'm scared and I'm alone.
Alone...
.. and very, very scared.
I confess.
I didn't leave Gallifrey
because I was bored!
That was a lie! It's always been a lie!
Not enough? You want more?
I was scared! I ran because I was scared!
Is that what you want me to
say? Is that true enough for you?
CREAKING
QUIET SNARLING
WIND HOWLS
MASONRY RUMBLES
LOUD RUMBLING
CLANKING
CLOCK TICKS
'It's funny, the day you
lose someone isn't the worst.
'At least you've got something to do.
'It's all the days they stay dead.'
FLIES BUZZ
57 minutes.
This is how my world works, Clara.
I tick off the seconds as they pass.
- DOOR THUDS
- My life is a countdown.
If I draw the creature to
one extreme of the castle,
and I run to the other extreme,
I can earn myself a maximum of 82 minutes.
82 minutes to eat,
sleep and work.
My work is finding Room 12.
The castle wants me to. It's luring me.
The numbering is a bit confused,
as if the rooms are all jumbled up.
Maybe they move around.
I saw the whole castle move...
.. when I made the creature stop.
HE SIGHS
Every room, if I leave it long enough,
reverts to its condition
at the moment I arrive.
It tidies up after itself.
Automated room service.
I think this whole place is
inside a closed energy loop,
constantly recycling.
Or maybe I'm in Hell?
That's OK. I'm not scared of Hell.
It's just Heaven for bad people.
But how long will I have to be here?
- FOOD TRICKLES OFF SPOON
- Forever?
DISTORTED CLATTERING
It's always coming.
- FOOTSTEPS THUD
- Always closer.
The countdown never stops.
But the countdown to what?
DOOR OPENS
There are two events in everybody's
life that nobody remembers,
two moments experienced
by every living thing.
Yet, no-one remembers anything about them.
Nobody remembers being born...
and nobody remembers dying.
Is that why we always stare
into the eye sockets of a skull?
Because we're asking,
"What was it like?
"Does it hurt?
"Are you still scared?"
"Bird"? What's "bird" got to do with it?
Are there birds here?
CLANGING
LOUD GRATING
PATTERING
There's something I'm missing, Clara,
and I think it's something terrible.
DOOR CREAKS OPEN AND SHUT
Hello?
Hello, is there someone there? Hello!
It's a trap, Clara.
A lure and a trap.
I'm following breadcrumbs laid out for me.
This is somebody's game...
.. and I can't stop playing,
a game everybody else has lost.
I know how to move that wall, Clara,
so long as I don't run out of confessions.
- But what I really want to know is...
- FLIES BUZZ
.. who's been playing
about with the stars?
They're all in the wrong places,
for this time zone, anyway.
I know I didn't time travel to get here.
I can FEEL time travel.
If I didn't know better, I'd
say I've travelled 7,000 years
into the future.
But I do know better.
So, who moved the stars?
FLIES BUZZ LOUDLY
The Hybrid.
Long before the Time War,
the Time Lords knew it was coming,
like a storm on the wind.
There were many prophecies and stories,
legends before the fact.
One of them was about a
creature called the Hybrid.
Half Dalek, half Time Lord --
the ultimate warrior.
But whose side would it be on?
Would it bring peace or destruction?
Was it real, or a fantasy?
I confess,
I know the Hybrid is real.
I know where it is, and what it is.
I confess, I'm afraid.
CREAKING
LOUD RUMBLING
HE PANTS
CLOCK TICKS LOUDLY
Of course!
The last square on the board.
What else would it be?
The Tardis.
One confession away.
SONIC SUNGLASSES HUM
Azbantium.
400 times harder than diamond.
20 feet thick.
The way out.
Bird!
LOUD WHOOSHING
CLAP ECHOES LOUDLY
That's when I remember!
Always then.
Always... then.
Always EXACTLY then!
I can't keep doing this, Clara! I can't!
Why is it always me? Why is
it never anybody else's turn?!
CHALK TAPS
Can't I just lose?
Just this once?!
Easy. It would be easy.
It would be SO easy.
Just tell them.
Just tell them, whoever wants
to know, all about the Hybrid.
FOOTSTEPS THUD AND FLIES BUZZ
I can't keep doing this.
I can't...
I can't always do this!
It's not fair!
Clara, it's just not fair!
Why can't I just lose?!
But I can remember, Clara.
You don't understand,
I can remember it all.
Every time.
And you'll still be gone.
Whatever I do...
.. you still won't be there.
Doctor...
.. you are not the only
person who ever lost someone.
It's the story of everybody.
Get over it.
Beat it.
Break free.
Doctor, it's time.
Get up, off your arse...
.. and win!
Hello again.
No more confessions, sorry.
FOOTSTEPS THUD AND FLIES BUZZ
But I will tell you... the truth.
HE SCREAMS
The Hybrid is a very dangerous secret.
A very, very dangerous secret
and it needs to be kept!
HE SHOUTS
So, I'm telling you
nothing. Nothing at all.
Instead, I'm going to
do something far worse.
Argh!
I'm going to get out of here,
and find whoever put me
here in the first place,
and whatever they're trying to
do, I'm going to... stop it!
Argh!
FOOTSTEPS THUD
But it might take me a little while,
so do you want me to tell you a story?
The Brothers Grimm, lovely fellas...
They're on my darts team.
Argh!
According to them,
there's this emperor
and he asks this shepherd's boy...
.."How many seconds in eternity?"
HISSING, HE SHRIEKS
FLIES BUZZ
WHOOSHING
POWERING DOWN
SILENCE
WHIRRING
POWERING UP
People always get it
wrong with Time Lords.
We take forever to die.
Even if we're too injured to regenerate,
every cell in our bodies keeps trying.
Dying properly,
can take days.
That's why we like to
die among our own kind.
They know not to bury us early.
HE GROANS
I think, in my current condition...
.. it'll take me about a day and a half
to reach the top of the tower.
I think.
If I'm lucky...
.. I have a day and a half.
HE STRAINS
I have to do this, Clara.
It's the only way.
I have to be strong.
I should have known
from the very beginning.
Of course.
The portrait of you,
the creature from my own nightmares...
This place is my own,
bespoke torture chamber...
.. intended for me only,
and all those skulls in the water...
How could there be other
prisoners... in my hell?
The answer, of course,
is there never were any other prisoners.
And the stars...
They weren't in the wrong place...
.. and I haven't time travelled.
I've just been here
a very, very long time.
Every room resets.
Remember I told you that?
Every room reverts to
its original condition.
Logically, the teleporter
should do the same.
"Teleporter" -- fancy word.
Just like 3D printers, really,
except they break down living matter
and information, and transmit it.
All you have to do is add energy.
The room has reset,
returned to its original
condition when I arrived.
That means there's a copy of me
still in the hard drive.
Me, exactly as I was...
.. when I first got here...
.. 7,000 years ago.
All I have to find is some energy.
And all you need for energy...
.. is something to burn.
ELECTRICAL BUZZING, HE GROANS
STATIC CRACKLING
HE GROANS
CLANKING
How long can I keep doing this, Clara?
Burning the old me...
.. to make a new one?
HISSING
HE GASPS FOR AIR
CLANKING
If you think because
she's dead, I am weak,
then you understand very little.
If you were any part of killing
her and you're not afraid,
then you understand nothing at all.
So, for your own sake, understand this.
I'm the Doctor. I'm coming to find you,
and I will never, ever stop.
DOOR GRATES SHUT
Because you won't see THIS coming!
SPLASHING
If I didn't know better,
I'd say I've travelled 7,000
years into the future.
Aah!
"How many seconds in eternity?"
HISSING, HE YELLS
HE GROANS
HISSING
HE GASPS FOR AIR
If I didn't know better, I'd
say I've travelled 12,000 years
into the future.
"How many seconds in eternity?"
- And the shepherd's boy...
- HE YELLS
HE GASPS FOR AIR
TINKLING
CREATURE SCREECHES
.. 600,000 years into the future.
Argh!
"How many seconds in eternity?"
And the shepherd's boy says...
Argh!
HE GASPS FOR AIR
SCREECHING
.. 1,200,000 years into the future.
.. And the shepherd's boy says...
Argh!
HE GASPS FOR AIR
.. Two million years into the future.
.. And the shepherd's boy says...
HE GASPS FOR AIR
CREATURE SCREECHES
.. 20 million years into the future.
Ow!
And the shepherd's boy says...
"There's this mountain of pure diamond.
"It takes an hour to climb it,
and an hour to go around it!"
HE GASPS FOR AIR
CREATURE SCREECHES
.. 52 million years.
"Every hundred years, a little bird comes
"and sharpens its beak on
the diamond mountain..."
HE GASPS FOR AIR
.. Nearly a billion years.
Argh!
".. And when the entire
mountain is chiselled away,
"the first second of
eternity will have passed!"
HE GASPS FOR AIR
.. Well over a billion years.
Argh!
You must think that's
a hell of a long time.
.. Two billion years.
Personally, I think that's a hell of a...
HE GASPS FOR AIR
Aaargh!
CRACKING
CRUMBLING
WIND HOWLS
CREATURE SCREECHES
METALLIC CLATTERING
Personally, I think
that's a hell of a bird.
LOUD CRASH
WIND HOWLS
WHOOSHING
MECHANICAL CLINKING
LIGHT FOOTSTEPS APPROACH
Go to the city.
Find somebody important.
Tell them, I'm back.
Tell them, I know what they did,
and I'm on my way.
And if they ask you who I am,
tell them, I came the long way round.
You can probably still hear me...
.. so just between ourselves...
.. you've got the prophecy wrong.
The Hybrid is not half Dalek.
Nothing is half Dalek. The
Daleks would never allow that.
The Hybrid destined to conquer Gallifrey
and stand in its ruins...
.. is me.
The Hybrid. I think it's
time to tell the truth.
I heard the Doctor had come home.
One so loves fireworks.
What's he up to?
The Hybrid is a creature
thought to be crossbred
from two warrior races.
I know I went too far.
You have broken every
code you ever lived by.
On my command!
Is it true?
- She's my friend.
- Fire!
Med-team to Sector 52,
extraction chamber seven.
Regeneration in progress.